Nemanja Ajvaz

Front End Developer

Profile

A results-driven full stack developer with a strong operational and technical skill set intended for building functional websites and applications. I graduated with a Web Development Certificate from the University of Sydney, where I gained experience in HTML, CSS, JQuery, Express.js, Node.js, SQL, MongoDB and Agile Methodologies. With 3+ years of industry experience in IT Operations and numerous awards I would like to turn my focus on the technical side of the industry to create the best user experience applications.

Employment History

Service Delivery Manager at AusNet Services (Formerly Mondo), Melbourne

July 2021 — Present

- Managing a defined customer portfolio supporting business growth and retention.
- Developing a sound understanding of the intricacies of the supported solution and the customer's needs.
- Operating as a conduit between the customer and our technical teams to drive optimal delivery of services or service technology.
- Putting the customer first; evaluating customer feedback and developing continual service improvement by establishing activities designed to ensure consistently high service performance.
- Ensuring customers have access to the right level of information on overall service performance and any planned outage and/or changes
- Strong focus on reducing costs and increasing efficiencies through the implementation of documented best practice processes.
- Estimating costs for upcoming work

Scrum Master at AusNet Services (Formerly Mondo), Melbourne

August 2020 — Present

During my time with the team I have administered all Agile/Scrum processes including sprint planning, daily scrums, sprint reviews and sprint retrospectives; coached team members and clients on Agile process. I have incorporated liberating structures in the sprint

retrospectives to facilitate team discussions.

- Assist in defining and deploying new product development processes and in facilitating the continuous improvement of existing processes.
- Empower the team to make system and process improvements captured in sprint retrospective meetings.
- Manage sprint backlog items and tasks.

Details

0415411879

nemanja.ajvaz@gmail.com

Links

Portfolio LinkedIn GitHub StackOverflow

Skills

Agile and Scrum

Interpersonal Skills

Emotional Intelligence

Teamwork

Analytical thinking and problem solving

Communication

Leadership

Jira

ITIL

SQL

JavaScript

jQuery

HTML

CSS

React

- Leading the teams efforts towards continuous improvement.
- Remove obstacles for developers and testers.
- Working effectively with others to remove delivery team roadblocks.
- Conducted workshops and team building activities to promote team happiness.

Application Support / Development Technician at AusNet Services (Formerly Mondo), Melbourne

November 2018 — July 2021

- Collaborating with developers to ensure client specifications are met.
- Tested troubleshooting methods, devised innovative solutions, and documented solutions for inclusion knowledge base for the support team to use.
- Conducted regression testing, analyzed results and submitted observations to the development team.
- Work closely with internal / external stakeholders, solution architects, managers and developers across locations to ensure timely delivery.
- Supporting other teams and areas of Ausnet when required to ensure the best and fastest resolutions to high priority issues.
- Working to define and diagnose issues by determining the root cause(s) of problems and providing resolution to customers, using a broad range of troubleshooting skills related to software functionality and data analysis.
- Produce functional and technical specifications for the development group to bridge any gaps in the core functionality and integration development
- Extensive SQL (Oracle) experience. I worte scripts that the team uses on a daily basis.

Application Support Analyst at AusNet Services (Formerly Mondo), Melbourne

March 2018 — November 2018

February 2021 — February 2021

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (Computing and Networking), Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology, Melbourne

February 2013 — November 2017

Web Development Bootcamp, University of Sydney

June 2021 — November 2021

Projects

Chirper, Melbourne

August 2021 — September 2021

Chirper was designed as a way to communicate with others on topics that interested you. A user would sign up and and could either create a chat or join an existing chat to communicate with others on topics of interest.

Repo: https://github.com/Nem-Ajvaz/Group_Project_2

Live Link: https://mysterious-bastion-78954.herokuapp.com/

Reel Movies, Melbourne

July 2021 — July 2021

This project will enable the user to search for a movie title in the search bar and and render the movie details (Title, Plot, Actors, Awards and Ratings) along with the YouTube trailer to the screen. We used two API's to acheive this: OMDb API and the Google API (Youtube), information regarding implementation will be discussed later on in the README.md.

The technologies used were: Javascript, Jquery, API and LocalStorage

Repo: https://nem-ajvaz.github/Nem-Ajvaz/Group_Project/

Live Link; https://nem-ajvaz.github.io/Group_Project/

Weather Forecast, Melbourne

June 2021 — June 2021

A simple weather forecast app for viewing a daily and 5-day forecast.

The technologies used were: Javascript, Jquery, API and LocalStorage.

Repo: https://nem-ajvaz.github/Nem-Ajvaz/homework_6/

Live Link: https://nem-ajvaz.github.io/homework_6/

Day Planner, Melbourne

June 2021 — June 2021

A simple calendar app for scheduling your working day.

Technologies used were: JavaScript and LocalStorage

Repo: https://nem-ajvaz.github/Nem-Ajvaz/homework_5/

Live Link: https://nem-ajvaz.github.io/homework_5/

Certification

Scrum Master

August 2020 — Present

https://www.scrum.org/user/703808

Sumo Logic Fundamentals, Melbourne

January 2019 — Present

Awards

Mondo Star Award for "We Deliver"

2019

Mondo Star Award for "We work Safely"

Mingle Stars Award - For constant support of his customers and his peers

2019

Mingle Stars Award - Instrumental in driving a resolution for a high severity incident

2019

◄ References

References available upon request